Finding aid for the Xavier University President's Office records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University President's Office records
1856-2013
1955-2004
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). President's Office
26.5 linear feet (50 boxes, 1 map case drawer, 1 piece)
This is a collection consisting chiefly of correspondence from and to various Xavier presidents. Other materials may also be included, such as news clippings, texts of speeches, obituaries and school related materials generated during the presidency of an individual Xavier president. Holdings for individual Xavier presidents prior to 1940 are either minimal or non-existent.
XUA-50
History of Xavier University Presidents
Founded in 1841 as St. Xavier College by the Society of Jesus, Xavier changed its name to Xavier University in 1930. As of 2014, thirty-four Xavier administrations (not including two interim administrations) encompass the history of the institution.Two Xavier presidents served as president on two separate occasions, Thomas O'Neil, S.J. (1869-1871 and 1879) and Edward A. Higgins, S.J. (1874-1879 and 1885-1887). Two interim administrations saw the presidency of laymen (Dr. Frank Mastrianna (1986) and Mr. Michael Conaton (1990-1991). Otherwise Xavier presidents have been members of the Society of Jesus.
The following is a chronological listing of the presidents of Xavier University: 1840-47, John A. Elet, S.J.; 1847-48, John E. Blox, S.J.; 1849-51, John DeBlieck, S.J.; 1851-53, George A. Carrell, S.J.; 1853-56, Isidore Boudreaux, S.J.; 1856-61, Maurice Oakley, S.J.; 1861-65, John Schultz, S.J.; 1865-69, Walter H. Hill, S.J.; 1869-71, Thomas O'Neil, S.J.; 1871-74, Leopold Bushart, S.J.; 1874-79, Edward A. Higgins, S.J.; 1879, Thomas O'Neil, S.J.; 1879-81, Rudolph J. Meyer, S.J.; 1881-84, John I. Coghlan, S.J.; 1884-85, Henry Moeller, S.J.; 1885-87, Edward A. Higgins, S.J.; 1887-93, Henry Schapman, S.J.; 1893-97, Alexander J. Burrowes, S.J.; 1897-1901, Michael J. O'Connor, S.J.; 1901-08, Albert J. Dierckes, S.J.; 1908-11, Joseph Grimmelsman, S.J.; 1911-17, Francis Heiermann, S.J.; 1917-22, James McCabe, S.J.; 1923-31, Hubert F. Brockman, S.J.; 1931-35, Hugo F. Sloctemyer, S.J.; 1935-40, Dennis F. Burns, S.J.; 1940-49, Celestin J. Steiner, S.J.; 1949-55, James F. Maguire, S.J.; 1955-72, Paul L. O'Connor, S.J.; 1972-1982, Robert W. Mulligan, S.J.; 1982-85, Charles L. Currie, S.J.; 1986, Dr. Frank Mastrianna (interim); 1986-90, Albert J. DiUlio, S.J.; 1991, Mr. Michael Conaton (interim); 1991-2000, James E. Hoff, S.J.; 2000-, Michael J. Graham, S.J..
Scope and Content
This collection encompasses chiefly correspondence files of the various Xavier presidents. Included may be other materials including speeches, news clippings and files reflecting Xavier activities during the presidency of individual presidents. Many earlier Xavier presidents are either not represented in this collection or only minimally represented.
Statement of Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series: 19th century presidents, 20th century presidents, and 21st century presidents. Each president's papers are then arranged by type or topic and then chronologically.
Separated Material
Photographs from James Hoff were separated and are unprocessed.
Related Material
Correspondence from presidents Hubert Brockman and Hugo Sloctemeyer can also be found in Folder Fred Hilvert, Biographical Files Collection, Xavier University Archives, Xavier University, Cincinnati, Ohio.
Correspondence from presidents Hubert Brockman and Celestin Steiner can also be found in Folder Susanna Hinkle, Biographical Files Collection, Xavier University Archives, Xavier University, Cincinnati, Ohio.
Restrictions on Access
More current materials entail restricted access. Please contact the Xavier University Archives staff.
Acquisition Information
Records include donation from Ernest Fontana, 2012 found in Box 7, Folder 4 (letters from Karl Wentersdorf to Paul O'Connor, 1970).
Accruals
Additions to this collection are expected.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)-- Administration; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)-- Presidents
Persons:
Brockman, Hubert F.; Burns, Dennis F.; Conaton, Michael J.; Currie, Charles L.; Dierckes, Albert J.; DiUlio, Albert J.; Graham, Michael J.; Heiermann, Francis; Hoff, James E.; Maguire, James F.; Mastrianna, Francis; McCabe, James; Mulligan, Robert W.; Oakley, Maurice; O'Connor, Paul L.; Steiner, Celestin J.; Sloctemyer, Hugo F.
Detailed Description of The Collection
- 19th Century Xavier Presidents, 1841-1900
  - Maurice Oakley, S.J., 1856-1861
    - Contemporary Catholic Telegraph excerpts and biographical information, 1854-1860 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Information on St. Xavier College during the presidency of Fr. Maurice Oakley, including the collapse of the wall of St. Xavier Church and the resulting death of thirteen workmen. Also included is biographical information on Fr. Oakley. Seemingly some pages are missing.
- 20th Century Xavier Presidents, 1901-2000
  - Albert Dierckes, S.J., 1901-1907
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1901,1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Francis Heiermann, S.J., 1911-1917
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1913-1916; 1947; undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Includes Fr. Heiermann's obituary.
  - James McCabe, S.J., 1917-1923
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1919-1926; undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hubert F. Brockman, S.J., 1923-1931
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence about Apologetics Class, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Death on February 12, 1931 and Funeral (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Hugo F. Sloctemyer, S.J., 1931-1935
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence and Papers and Death (1937), 1935 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Dennis F. Burns, S.J., 1935-1940
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1936-1938 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1939-1941 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Celestin J. Steiner, S.J., 1940-1949
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - James F. Maguire, S.J., 1949-1955
    - Biographical Data, 1949-1955; 1970; 1973; 2000 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence and Papers, 1950-1955 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Annual Reports on Xavier University, 1949-1955 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Speeches, 1949-1955; undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Paul O'Connor, S.J., 1955-1972
    Various awards of Fr. Paul L. O'Connor, S.J. can be found housed separately in the Xavier University Archives. A listing of awards is found with this separate collection. The box is labeled "XUA-50, President's Office records, Paul L. O'Connor Awards."
    Various items from the office of Fr. Paul L. O'Connor, S.J. are also housed separately in the Xavier University Archives. A listing of box contents is included. The box is labeled "XUA-50, President's Office records, Personal Office Items."
    - Biographical Information, 1946-1974; undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Awards and Citations (Folder 1), 1964-1974 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Awards and Citations (Folder 2), 1949-1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Awards and Citations (Folder 3), 1952-1973 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - As Naval Chaplain (Folder 1), 1944-1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - As Naval Chaplain (Folder 2), 1945-1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence about Trip to Rome, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence about Memberships in Clubs, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence about Retirement from Presidency, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence as Trustee at Canisius College, Buffalo, NY, 1969-1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Death and Funeral, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Annual Reports on the State of Xavier University, 1955-1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence, 1954-1957 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - General Correspondence, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - General Correspondence, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - General Correspondence, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - General Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - General Correspondence, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - General Correspondence, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence about University Dinners, 1955-1971 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence about Clergy Dinners, 1959-1972 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence about Faculty Tuition Remission, 1957-1973 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence about the Ford Foundation College Grants Program, 1954-1968 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence about the Ganser-Gerber Visits, 1956-1958 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with Individuals, 1956-1974 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      This file consists of correspondence and related materials for the following individuals: Martin G. Dumler, Roger H. Ferger, Leo G. Kuhlman, Bishop Edward A. McCarthy, Fred Lazarus, Jr. and Family, Joseph A. Verkamp, and Mr. and Mrs. Russell J. Walker.
    - Correspondence with the Jesuit Community, 1959-1971 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with Jesuit Superiors, 1955-1965 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with Jesuit Superiors, 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with Jesuit Superiors, 1968-1973 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with Walter C. Langsam, 1957; 1971 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence about Milford Novitiate and Farm, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence about Pooled Income Fund, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence about Procter & Gamble and Support for Xavier's Hospital Administration Program, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence about Rhodes House/Center, 1962-1966 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence about Scholarships, 1970-1974 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence about Timken Company Scholarship Program, 1967-1974 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence concerning Wills and Bequests, 1954-1972 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence Concerning Wills and Bequests, 1952-1964 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence concerning Gifts, Wills, and Bequests, 1956-1961 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence concerning Day of Community Awareness on Vietnam, October 15, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence about Controversies Over Guest Speakers, 1964-1971 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence concerning Conference of Christians and Jews, 1958-1969 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence about the Chaswil Foundation Student Loan Fund at Xavier, 1950-1967 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence about Proposed Affiliation of Chase Law School with Xavier University (Folder 1), 1964-1966 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence about Proposed Affiliation of Chase Law School with Xavier University (Folder 2), 1968-1970 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with Bishops and Chancery, 1946-1974 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence concerning the Advancement Fund Drive, 1972-1974 (Proposed Gifts), 1967-1974 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence concerning the Advancement Fund Drive, 1972-1974 (Proposed Gifts) (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence Concerning the Advancement Fund Drive, 1972-1974 (Proposed Gifts) (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence Concerning the Advancement Fund Drive, 1972-1974 (Proposed Gifts), 1971-1973 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence Concerning the Advancement Fund Drive, 1972-1974 (Gift Proposals), 1958-1973 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence Concerning the Advancement Fund Drive, 1972-1974 (Steering Committee and Summer Bridge) (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence Concerning the Advancement Fund Drive, 1972-1974 List of Prospective Donors, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence Concerning the Advancement Fund Drive, 1972-1974 Reports (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Speech: Alumni 75th Annual Dinner, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Speeches: Alumni Living Endowment Fund, 1963-1967 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Speeches: Alter Hall Ground Breaking and Dedication, 1959-1960 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Speech: Commencement at Mt. St. Mary's Seminary, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Speech: Universal Communion Sunday, 1967 March 12 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Speeches: Alumni Association Meetings, 1959-1968 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Speech: Armco Steel Company/ Founder's Day, 1956 April 20 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Speech: Baccalaureate Sermon at University of Akron, 1961 June 11 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Speech: Baccalaureate Talk at Miami University, 1964 June 7 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Speech: Baccalaureate Talk at Mt. St. Joseph College, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Speech: Baccalaureate Talk at Ohio University, 1959 Ju ne 7 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Speech: Basketball Banquet Talks, 1957-1968 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Speech: Booklovers Meeting, 1966 September 19 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Speech: Breakfast Exchange Club (BMX), 1966 March 2 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Speech: Conference of Christians and Jews Dinner, 1962 February 20 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Speech: National Secretaries Association Dinner, 1962 February 15 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Speeches: Businessmen Mobilized for Xavier, 1960; 1964-1969 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Speeches: Knights of Columbus Lunch, 1955; 1958 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Speech: Catholic War Veterans, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Speeches: Commercial Club Meeting and National Office Management Association, 1958; 1965 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Speech: Cincinnati Historical Society, 1971 December 13 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Speech: Commencement at Athenaeum, 1958 December 22 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Speeches: Football Banquets, 1955-1969 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Speeches: Freshman Orientations, 1957-1970 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Speech: Friends of Orphans Banquet, 1956 November 8 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Speech: Santa Clara Workshop, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Speech: Msgr. Gressle's Golden Jubilee, 1959 June 16 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Speech/Editorial: Hamilton County Board of Education, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Speech/Article: Holy Cross Quarterly, 1969-1970 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Speech: Holy Name Breakfast, St. Agnes, Lookout Heights, KY, 1960 March 13 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Speech: Jesuit Educational Association, 1960 April (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Speeches: Dad's Club Meeting and Fathers-Sons Meeting, 1957; 1962 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Speech: Irish Fellowship Club (50th Anniversary), 1961 March 17 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Speech: Jesuit Family Club at St. Xavier High School, 1960 January 21 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Speech: Cincinnati Bar Association "Law Day", 1964 April (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Speech: Living Endowment Fund Blue Ribbon Dinner, 1969 June 5 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Speech: Xavier Alumni on Liberal Arts, 1949 March (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Speech: Wedding Homily, 1968 October 5 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Speech: Mathematicians Conference, 1959 January 31 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Speech: ROTC Commissioning Ceremony, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Speeches: Funeral Sermons, 1957-1972 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Various Speeches (Folder One), 1952-1972 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Various Speeches et al. (Folder Two), 1954-1968; undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Speech: Council of Jewish Women (Rockdale Temple), 1964 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Speech: Community Leaders' Forum (Red Cross Building), 1956 October 4 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Speech: Welcome to Fr. Mulligan, Provost, 1971 February 15 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Speech: Musketeer Club (Special Gifts), undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Speech: Musketeer Annual Athletic Appeal Kickoff (MAAA), 1973 September 6 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1954-1963 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Speech: The Religious Teacher (Notre Dame), 1952 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Speech: JEA Presidents' Meeting Relationship with Diocesan Authority, 1959 January 4 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Speech: Church of the Air Program, WKRC Radio, 1956 May 25 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Speech: Presidential ROTC Review, 1972 May 10 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Speech: Rotary Club, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Speech: Mass Sermons, 1956-1965 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Speech: Santa Clara Deans' Institute Social Life of Students, 1955 August 3 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Speech: National Catholic Educational Association Meeting, 1952 April 17 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Speech: The Teacher, undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Speech: American Red Cross, 1963 March 26 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Speech: Sons of American Revolution Dinner, 1962 February 21 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Speech: Lawyers' "Red Mass" Sermon The University and the Law, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Speech: Friendly Sons of St. Patrick Dinner, 1964 March 17 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Speech: Dedication of the Xavier University Center, 1965 October 31 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Speech: Necomen Society Vidit Mirabilia Magna, 1955-1956; 1971 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Speech: Commencement at Borromeo Seminary, Wickliffe, Ohio, 1966 June 4 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Speech: Commencement at Chase Law School, 1967 June 1 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Speech: Commencement at Fayetteville High School, 1966 May 27 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Speech: Commencement at Fenwick High School, Middletown, Ohio, 1967 June 4 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Speech: Commencement at Good Samaritan Hospital School of Nursing, 1957-1964 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Speech: Commencement at Hamilton Catholic High School, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Speech: Commencement at LaSalle High School, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Speech: Commencement at Loyola Academy Class of 1958, 1958 June 10 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Speech: Commencement at Maderia High School and Roger Bacon High School, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Speech: Commencement at Moeller High School, 1967 June 8 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Speech: Commencement at College of Mount St. Joseph, 1960 June 6 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Speech: Commencement at Nazareth College, Nazareth, Kentucky, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Speech: Commencement at Ohio State University, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Speech: Commencement at Our Lady of Cincinnati College, 1957 June 4 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Speech: Commencement at Police Recruitment School, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 15)
      The actual text of the speech is missing.
    - Speech: Commencement at Purcell High School, 1958 June 5 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Speech: Commencement at St. Ignatius High School, Chicago, IL, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Speech: Commencement at St. Ignatius High School, Cleveland, OH, 1960 June 9 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Speech: Commencement at St. John's College, Cleveland, OH, 1966 June 4 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Speech: Commencement at St. John's High School, Toledo, OH, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Speech: Commencement at St. Mary of the Woods College, 1958 June 2 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Speech: Commencement at St. Mary's, Lake Leelanau, Michigan, 1960 May 29 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Speech: Commencement at St. Vincent High School, Akron, Ohio, 1959 May 31 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Speech: Commencement at St. Xavier High School, 1960 June 12 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Speech: "The Communicator," Hamilton County Office of Education, 1970 January (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Speech: Conference of Christians and Jews, 1959 May 18; undated (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Speech: American Institute of Banking Dinner, 1960 March 24 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Speech: Dads' Club Party Line Meeting, 1958 April 29 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Speech: Seventh Presbyterian Church On Ecumenism, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Speeches: Estate Planning Seminars, 1965-1969 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Speech: Ecumenical Service at Middletown High School, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Speeches: Faculty Meetings, 1960-1972 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Speech: Family Financial Planning Seminar, 1971 January 24 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations: Jesuit Educational Association Conference of Jesuit Presidents, 1959-1966 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Jesuit Educational Association Conference of Jesuit Presidents, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Jesuit Educational Association Conference of Jesuit Presidents, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Association of Urban Universities to the National Commission on Accrediting, 1961-1969 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations National Commission on Accrediting (Executive Committee), 1970-1971 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Interim Educational Television Study Commission, 1959-1961 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Interim Educational Television Study Commission, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Commission on Education Beyond the High School, 1957-1958 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Commission on Education Beyond the High School, 1956-1958 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Commission on Education Beyond the High School, 1957-1961 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Commission on Education Beyond the High School, 1957-1958 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Commission on Education Beyond the High School, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Commission on Education Beyond the High School, 1956-1958 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Memberships in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Commission on Education Beyond the High School, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Higher Education Assistance Commission, 1962-1963 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Higher Education Assistance Commission, 1963-1964 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Higher Education Assistance Commission, 1964-1965 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Membership in Off Campus Organizations Ohio Higher Education Assistance Commission, 1963-1966 (Box 20, Folder 1)